Guide to the Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V:The United Nations Period And Related Files
  - Subseries V.5: Subject Files
    - Sub-subseries V.5.4: Rang-Jensen Case
      - *(RESTRICTED) Correspondence Folder: (Box 177#)
        - News media (Box 177#)
        - Organizations and individuals (Box 177#)
      - "Desk papers" --B-J, 1 Folder (see Office of Personnel memo, 27 January 1959) (Box 177#)
      - Disappearance and death November 1959
        - Condolences sent by Secretary-General and Mr. Cordier (Box 177#)
        - Letters and telegrams received (Box 177#)
        - Press comment and articles (Box 177#)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Press Releases and Background papers: (Box 178#)
        - Press releases and.Background papers 1957-1960 --1 complete set (Box 178#)
        - UN Statement of Facts, 15 December 1959 (drafts and final text) (Box 178#)
      - US Senate, Sub-committee report 14 September 1961 (Box 178#)
      - Spare copies Folder:
        - *(RESTRICTED) Administrative Tribunal verbatims 1958 (2 copies) (Box 178#)
        - Cables (Box 178#)
        - Correspondence, memos, statements 1957-l958 (Box 178#)
      - Press releases, background papers, press conference 1957-1960 (Box 178#)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.5: Disarmament
      - Background papers (Box 179)
      - AWC "Working" file (misc. papers) (Box 179)
      - SG Statement 28 April 1960 and other papers (Box 179)
      - Documents:
        - Disarmament Commission documents (Box 179)
        - Disarmament Commission verbatims (Box 179)
        - "A" documents (General Assembly) (Box 179)
        - "A/Cl" documents (Box 179)
        - "S" documents (Security Council) (Box 179)
      - Ten Nation Disarmament Committee, 1960
        - Cables (Box 179)
        - Documents (Box 179)
        - Press Releases (Box 179)
        - Reporting letters from Geneva (Box 180)
        - Summaries of meetings (Box 180)
        - SG correspondence (Box 180)
        - Verbatim records –I & 2 (Box 180)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.6: Guatemala
      - Guatemalan Question 1954 (Box 181)
      - Security Council documents (Box 181)
      - UN and Regional Organizations (Box 181)
      - "Working" Papers (Box 181)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.7: Hungary
      - *(RESTRICTED) Cables 1956-1961 (code and clear, Geneva, London other) (Box 182)
      - Cab1es 1958 (clear) ? (Box 182)
      - Documents: G/A 1956-1961 (Box 182)
      - Human Rights matters (Box 182)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers (Box 182)
      - Press Releases (UN and other) 1956-1960 (Box 182)
      - Relief Assistance to Refugees, correspondence, memos, etc. 1956-1957 (under G/A res.) (Box 182)
      - Secretary-General's exchanges with Hungarian Gov.(aides memoire, notes verba1e, cable, 1956) (Box 182)
      - GA Resolutions (Box 182)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Technical Assistance, Hungarian request for, 1957 (Box 183)
      - Trials 1957 Secretary-General's personal appeal (Box 183)
      - UN Observer group of three, (Gunderson, Lal1 and L1eras) (Box 183)
      - UN Radio Broadcasts (complaint of US.) (Box 183)
      - UN Special Representative, Prince Wan Waithayakon 1956-1958 (?) (Box 183)
      - UN Special Representative, Sir Leslie Munro 1958-1962 (Box 183)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Special Committee on the Problem of Hungary:
        - Reports (Box 183)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers (Box 183)
      - Humphrey Trevelyan: one working file entitled "Correspondence" (Box 184)
      - Dr. Protitch working files: (not examined by D. G.):
        - 1. Observer Group of Three, 4 November-12 December 1956 (Box 184)
        - 2. "Different communications, letters and actions in connection with Hungarian situation 1956-1957 (contains two separate fo10ders: 1956 and 1957) (Box 184)
        - 3. "Different communications, letters and actions in connection with Hungarian situation during work of Special Committee in Europe" 1957 (Box 184)
        - 4. "Different communications, letters and actions in connection with Hungarian situation" 1958 (Box 184)
        - 5. "Meetings of Special Committee on Hungary, December 1957-January 1958) (Box 184)
        - 6. "Administrative Arrangements in connection with the work of Secretariat for the Special Committee." 1957 (Box 184)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.8: Middle East
      - UN Emergency Force: (Box 185#)
      - Cables: UNEF (Cairo) UNEFCA Clear and code 1956-1957, 1957-1959 (two files) (Box 185#)
      - UNEF(Capodachino) Clear and code, 1956-1958 (Box 185#)
      - UNEF (code and clear):
        - Vol. I Nov-December 19-56 code and clear (Box 185#)
        - Vol. II Jan-February 1957 code and clear (Box 185#)
        - Vol. III March 1957 code and clear (Box 186#)
        - Vol. IV April-May 1957 code and clear (Box 186#)
        - Vol. V June-December 19.57 code and clear (Box 186#)
        - Vol. VI Jan-October 1958 Code only (Box 186#)
        - Vol. VII November 1958-0ct. 1959 Code only (Box 187#)
        - Vol. VIII Sep. 1959-December 1960 Code only (Box 187#)
        - Vol. IX Jan 1961-February 1962 Code only (Box 187#)
        - Vol. VI 1959 Clear only (Box 187#)
        - Vol. VII 1960-1961 Clear only (Box 188)
        - Vol. VIII 1961 Clear only (Box 188)
      - UNEF Withdrawal 1967 (documents, press releases) (Box 188)
      - UNEF documents Folder (SG reports, etc. 1956-1958) (Box 188)
      - *(RESTRICTED) UNEF Advisory Committee verbatims, Vo1s. I, II, III (Confidential, restrictions not received from UN (Box 189)
      - Airlift summaries (Box 189)
      - Administrative and Financial arrangements (Box 189)
      - *(RESTRICTED) General Burns (correspondence, memos) (Box 189)
      - Cairo Office (Box 189)
      - Countries supplying units (correspondence with) (Box 189)
      - Deployment (Box 189)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Egypt, negotiations with (SG file) (conf.) (Box 190)
      - Egypt, agreement with ,1956 (Box 190)
      - Egypt, aide memoire by Dag Hammarskjold August 1957 re agreement with Egypt (copy) (Box 190)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Egypt, Treatment of British, French, Jewish residents (Box 190)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Evacuation policy, Specialized Agencies staff (Box 190)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Enforcement, ceasefire and arrangements for Force (Box 190)
      - Force Growth (Box 190)
      - Logistics (Box 190)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and memoranda (Box 190)
      - Offers of Units (Box 190)
      - Position of Troops (not complete) (Box 190)
      - Postal Plan (Box 190)
      - Press Releases (Box 190)
      - Press Clippings (Box 190)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Prisoner of War Exchange (Box 191)
      - Regulations (Box 191)
      - Secretariat Committee re organization and operation of UNEF (Box 191)
      - Situation reports (Box 191)
      - SWISSAIR contract (Box 191)
      - *(RESTRICTED) UN High Commissioner for Refugees (refugees from Egypt) (Box 191)
      - *(RESTRICTED) UNEF-UNTSO relations (Box 191)
      - United Kingdom --exchange of communications re cease fire and international force (SG file) (conf.) (Box 191)
      - Suez Canal:
        - General Assembly, 14th Session; excerpts from statements by representatives (Box 191)
        - Suez Canal Authority (Box 191)
        - Suez Canal Company (Box 191)
        - Constantinople Convention 1888 (Box 191)
        - Economic Data Report (Box 191)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Passage of Israeli Ships (Box 191)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Passage of Israeli Ships (ASTYPALEA), (2 Folders) (Box 191)
        - Suez Settlement Generally (Box 191)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Suez Canal Users Association (Box 191)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Clearance (Box 192)
        - Agreement, Egypt-United Nations (Box 192)
        - *(RESTRICTED) CivilianWatch (Box 192)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Correspondence, aides memoire (SG file?) (Box 192)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Costs (Box 192)
        - Dredging (Box 192)
        - Financing (Box 192)
        - "Lemsterkerk" (Box 192)
        - Maps (Box 192)
        - Marooned ships (Box 192)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Miscellaneous correspondence, memos, cables (Box 192)
        - Port Said Salvage operations (Box 192)
        - Press Releases (Box 193)
        - Salvor Companies (Box 193)
        - SG Report on Clearance (drafts) (Box 193)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Surcharged (Box 193)
        - UN Plan and Progress Reports (Box 193)
      - Arab Federation (Box 193)
      - Egypt-Cairo Synagogues, safety of religious books &: other objects 1957 (Box 193)
      - Egypt (UAR) Exchanges of correspondence with Secretary-General 1956-1960 (copies) (Box 193)
      - *(RESTRICTED) General file of correspondence and memos (1956-1960) (Box 193)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Israel, exchanges of correspondence with Secretary-General 1956-1961 aides memoires (Box 193)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Israel, meetings with Israel representatives 1957-1960 (reports on) (Box 193)
      - Iraq, exchange of correspondence, 1958 (Box 193)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Syria-Israel, Background paper (Box 193)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Troop build-ups, Syria, Israel, Jordan 1956 (Box 193)
      - UAR, establishment of, 1958 (Box 193)
      - General Armistice Agreements 1948 (Box 194)
        - Treaty Series Vol 42 (Box 194)
        - Armistice Agreements generally; 1 document, 1 aide memoire--1956,1957 (Box 194)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Egypt-Israel (Box 194)
        - Jordan-Israel:
          - Memoranda, correspondence (Mount Scopus) 1958-1961 (Box 194)
          - Documents 1961 (Box 194)
      - Syria-Israel 1960 (Box 194)
      - Hammarskjold trip, 6 Apr-3 Nay 1956 (Box 194)
      - Security Council Documents: 1956-1961 (Box 194)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Gaza Strip: 1956-1957 (Box 195)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Jordan:
        - Background paper 1959 (Box 195)
        - Communications with Govt. of Jordan (Box 195)
        - UN Mission, Spinelli 1958-1959 correspondence, etc. (Box 195)
        - UN Mission, cables 1958-1960 (1 file clear cables; 1 file code cables) (Box 195)
      - Lebanon Crisis 1958
        - Consultative Group (composition, correspondence, minutes) (Box 195)
        - Correspondence with Government (Box 195)
        - Miscellaneous file (background papers, correspondence, etc.) (Box 195)
        - Press releases (Box 195)
        - SG statements (Security Council; to press) (Box 195)
      - Documents:
        - General Assembly documents (Box 195)
        - Resolutions (G/A and S/C) (Box 195)
        - Secretary-General's reports to Security Council (Box 195)
        - Security Council documents (Box 195)
        - Security Council documents: Reports of UN Observation Group in Lebanon (UNOGIL) (Box 195)
      - Cables: (Box 196)
        - UNOGIL clear cables, vols. I and II, 1958 (Box 196)
        - *(RESTRICTED) UNOGIL code cables, vols. 1, II and III, 1958 (Box 196)
      - United Nations Relief And Works Agency: (Box 197)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Correspondence file, 1949-1960 (Box 197)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Cables, 1960-1962 (Box 197)
      - Middle East:
        - *(RESTRICTED) UNTSO Cables (United Nations Truce Supervision Organization) (Box 197)
        - UNTSO codes 1957-1962 --6 vols. (IX, X, XI, XII, XIII,XIV) (Vols. I-VIII missing) (Box 198#-199#)
        - UNTSO clears 1958-1962--9 vols. (do not appear to be in consecutive order, but would need to be examined more closely) (Box 200-201)
    - Sub-subseries V.5.9: Nuclear Tests
      - *(RESTRICTED) Nuclear Tests Conference, Geneva (1960-1962): (Box 202)
        - Code cables (Box 202)
        - Clear cables (Box 202)
        - Miscellaneous papers (Box 202)
        - Narayan reports from Geneva (Box 202)
  - Subseries V.6: The Public Papers of the Secretaries General of the United Nations
    Public Papers of the Secretaries-General of the United Nations (printed volumes 1-4, 6-7 are shelved at end of collection)
    - Sub-subseries V.6.1: Trygve Lie
      - Trygve Lie: 1945 -1948 A-B (Box 203)
      - 1948 C-Z, 1949 A-O (Box 204)
      - 1949 P-Z, 1950 A-K (Box 205)
      - 1950 O-Z -1951 (Box 206)
      - 1952-1954 Miscellaneous, A-P (Box 207)
      - Miscellaneous, S-Z; Press Conferences, 1946-1952 (Box 208)
      - Manuscripts and related correspondence (Box 209)
    - Sub-subseries V.6.2: Dag Hammarskjold: 1953 -1954
      - 1954 -1955 (Box 211)
      - 1956 (Box 212)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 213)
      - 1958 -1959 (Box 214)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 215)
      - 1960 -1961 (Box 216)
      - 1961 Speeches, miscellany (Box 217)
      - Manuscript, 1953-1956 (Box 218)
      - 1957-1959 (Box 219)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 220)
      - Related correspondence, manuscripts and miscellany (Box 221)
    - Sub-subseries V.6.3: U Thant 1961 -1963
      - 1963, 1964 (Box 223)
      - 1965 -1966 (Box 224)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 225)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 226)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 227)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 228)
      - 1971 Miscellaneous (Box 229)
    - Sub-subseries V.6.4: Miscellaneous correspondence and related items
      - U Thant Manuscript, 1961 -1963 (Box 230)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 231)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 232)
      - 1968-1971 (Box 233)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and related items (Box 234)
    - Sub-subseries V.6.5: Index to Public Papers
      - Index to Public Papers (card file): (Box 235)
        - Drawer A -Trygve Lie (Box 235)
        - Drawer B Dag Hammarskjold (Box 235)
        - Drawer A -U Thant (Box 236)
        - Drawer B -Kurt Waldheim (Box 236)
  - Subseries V.7: United Nations Bibliography and Miscellany
    - Bibliography of works relating to the United Nations (2 card files) (Box 237)
    - United Nations-miscellaneous (Box 238)
  - Subseries V.8:The Dag Hammarskjold Foundation
    - General File: (Box 239)
      - Book Project (Box 239)
      - Bronze Plaque Ceremony (Box 239)
      - Correspondence, (2 Folders) (Box 239)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 240)
      - Crary, Miner D., Jr. (Box 240)
      - Davies, David (Box 240)
      - Establishment of the Foundation (Box 240)
      - Hammarskjold, Bo, (2 Folders) (Box 240)
      - International Peace Research Institute (Box 240)
      - Leopold (Box 240)
      - Memo to Executive Committee (Box 240)
      - Memorial Coin (Box 240)
      - Michanek, Ernst (Box 240)
      - New York City Memorial Project (Box 240)
      - Pearson, Lester (Box 240)
      - Progress Report No. 1 (Box 240)
      - Relationship of DHF with National Committees (Box 240)
      - Reports to Blaustein, Cordier and Gross (Box 240)
      - Seminars -General Information (Box 241)
      - stamp (Box 241)
      - Stockholm (Box 241)
      - Sweden (Box 241)
      - UN Concerts (Box 241)
      - Van Dusen, Henry P. (Box 241)
      - Volunteers (Box 241)
    - Board Correspondence:
      - Ascoli, Max (Box 242)
      - Baker, John C. (Box 242)
      - Barnes, Djuna (Box 242)
      - Benjamin, Robert (Box 242)
      - Bernstein, Leonard (Box 242)
      - Bing, Rudolf (Box 242)
      - Black, Eugene (Box 242)
      - Blaustein, Jacob, (8 Folders) (Box 242)
      - Bunche, Ralph J. (Box 242)
      - Cordier, Andrew, (5 Folders) (Box 243)
      - Cowles, Gardner (Box 243)
      - Eichelberger, Clark (Box 243)
      - Ford, Henry II (Box 243)
      - Goheen, Robert F. (Box 243)
      - Gross, Ernest A. (Box 243)
      - Graham, Frank. (Box 243)
      - Harrison, Wallace (Box 243)
      - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr. (Box 243)
      - Hoffman, Paul G. (Box 243)
      - Hotchkis, Preston (Box 243)
      - Johnson, H.F. (Box 243)
      - Kirk, Grayson (Box 243)
      - Johnson, Joseph E. (Box 243)
      - Labouisse, Henry R. (Box 243)
      - Lasker, Mary (Mrs. Albert D.) (Box 243)
      - Lippman, Walter (Box 243)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot (Box 243)
      - Luce, Henry (Box 243)
      - Meany, George (Box 243)
      - Morse, David (Box 243)
      - Moses, Robert (Box 243)
      - Nimitz, Chester W. (Box 243)
      - Nolde, O. Frederick (Box 243)
      - O'Neill, Mrs. Eugene (Box 244)
      - Ormandy, Eugene (Box 244)
      - Pate, Maruice (Box 244)
      - Reuther, Walter (Box 244)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Box 244)
      - Salomon, Irving (Box 244)
      - Sockman, Ralph W. (Box 244)
      - Spellman, Francis Cardinal (Box 244)
      - Steinbeck, John (Box 244)
      - stevenson, Adlai E. (Box 244)
      - Thorp, Willard L. (Box 244)
      - Truman, Harry S. (Box 244)
      - Wadsworth, James ,T. (Box 244)
      - Wagner, Robert F. (Box 244)
      - Watson, Thomas J., Jr. (Box 244)
      - Zeckendorf, William (Box 244)
    - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1962-1967 (Folders) (Box 245)
    - Board of Trustees Meetings -Notebooks (Box 246)
    - Financial Files, General: (Box 247)
      - Booth Information (Box 247)
      - Budgets (Box 247)
      - Booth at UN (Box 247)
      - Chase Manhattan Bank (Box 247)
      - Chemical Bank of NY Trust (Box 247)
      - Chemical Bank NY Trust Company (Box 247)
      - Dime Savings Bank of Williamsburgh (Box 247)
      - Drexel & Co. Financial Reports 1962-1965, (4 Folders) (Box 247)
      - Financial statements (22 loose items) (Box 247)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 247)
      - Form Letters (Box 247)
      - Fund Drive, 1965 (Box 248)
      - Fund Raising Reports (Box 248)
      - Irving Trust (Box 248)
      - Kings County Savings Bank (Box 248)
      - Marine Midland Trust Company of New York (Box 248)
      - Office Contributions (Box 248)
      - Payroll Records and Tax Returns (Box 248)
      - Petty Cash Reports (Box 248)
      - Security .Transfer Forms (Box 248)
      - Smith Barney Company (Box 248)
      - Social Welfare Registration (Box 248)
      - Stock Portfolio (Box 248)
      - Tax Exemption (Box 248)
      - Taxes Federal (Box 248)
      - Taxes State (Box 248)
    - Financial Files -Accounts Payable -1965 (Box 249)
      - 1966 (Box 249)
      - Arcade Cleaners (Box 249)
      - Beaux Arts Shoppe (Box 249)
      - Rooks (Sweden) (Box 249)
      - Century Letter Company (Box 249)
      - Columbia University (Box 249)
      - Copease Corporation (Box 249)
      - Dag Hammarskjold Lectures (Box 249)
      - Dalo Button & Emblem Co. (Box 249)
      - Denver Leadership Training conference (Box 249)
      - Graphic Industries (Box 249)
      - Entertainment and Hospitality (Box 249)
      - Hooven Letters Inc. (Box 249)
      - Hospitalization (Box 249)
      - Insurance (Box 249)
      - Malcolm & Hayes, Inc. (Box 249)
      - Medallion (Box 250)
      - International Business Machines (Box 250)
      - Memorial Lectures (Box 250)
      - Messenger Services (Box 250)
      - Misc. Accounts, A-F (Box 250)
      - G-L (Box 250)
      - M-R (Box 250)
      - S-Z (Box 250)
      - New York Telephone Company (Box 250)
      - Office Rental (Box 250)
      - Payroll Records, 1962-1965, (3 Folders) (Box 250)
      - Pelzer Printers and Stationers (Box 250)
      - Pittsburgh Program (Box 250)
      - Prentice-Hall Corporation System (Box 250)
      - Random House (Box 250)
      - Tardino, V. J. (Box 250)
      - Terminal Letter Co., Inc. (Box 250)
      - Travel Expenses (Box 250)
      - United Nations (Box 250)
    - Financial Files -Cash Receipts and Disbursements (Box 251)
    - The Quest for Peace -Lecture Series and Book (Box 252)
    - U.S. Committee for the Dag Hammarskjöld Foundation (Box 253­254)
    - Photographs, tape, film, stamps (Box 255)
    - Printed memorabilia (Box 256)
  - Subseries V.9: Miscellaneous Studies, Reports and Projects, 1948-1971
    - Brookings Seminar on Problems of American Foreign Policy, 1947, 1948 (5 vols.) Foreign Policy Association -Volume of descriptive material Preliminary Guide to Exemplary Programs in Residential Continuing Education (197 The Future Character and Role of Peace Observation Arrangements Under the U.N. (Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research, 1964) David B. Truman -articles (1 Folder) (Box 257)
- Series VI: The Columbia University Period And Related Files
  - Administration, Miscellaneous (architectural plans, studies, and correspondence and miscellaneous items, ca. 1960-1969) (Box 258)
  - Cordier Seminars (transcripts, syllabi and related items, 1963-1964) (Box 259)
  - Dinners, Receptions and Engagements, 1969-1970 (Box 260­262)
  - World Trip, 1962 (Box 263)
  - General Files: (Box 264)
    - American Council on Education (Box 264)
    - Asian Consultative Conference, 1965 (Box 264)
    - Biblical Seminary in New York (Box 264)
    - Bio-Bibliographies (Box 264)
    - Biogaphical File (Box 264)
    - Bloch, Henry S. -Reports, (2 Folders) (Box 264)
    - Church of the Brethren (Box 265)
    - Columbia University -Miscellaneous (Box 265)
    - Colgate, May 1971 (Box 265)
    - Columbia Honorary Degree -Investiture (Box 265)
    - Columbia University -Hamilton Award (Box 265)
    - Columbia University Press Releases (Box 265)
    - Columbia University Presidency, (2 Folders) (Box 265)
    - Columbia University Charter Day (Box 265)
    - Cordier, Dorothy (re Death: 4 Folders) (Box 266)
    - Cordier, Dorothy, Fellowship Fund, (7 Folders) (Box 266)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 267)
    - Correspondence, Carbons, 1974-1976 (Box 267)
    - Deanship (Box 267)
    - Denver/Aspen (Box 267)
    - Dissertation: (Box 267)
    - Bishop (Box 267)
    - Khouw Bien Tie (Box 267)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 268)
    - Fund Raising (Box 268)
    - Germany, Federal Republic of (Box 268)
    - Honorary Degrees (Box 268)
    - Indiana Academy (Box 268)
    - International Council for Educational Development, 1971-1972 (Box 268)
    - Japan (Box 268)
    - Japan International Christian University (Box 268)
    - Japan International Christian University, (7 Folders) (Box 268)
    - Juniata College, 197? (Box 268)
    - Kirk, Grayson (Box 268)
    - Knights of Malta (Box 268)
    - General Files: (Box 270)
    - Manchester College (Box 270)
    - Manchester College (Box 271)
    - Mexico (Box 271)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 271)
    - Nobel Peace Prize (Box 271)
    - Nobel Peace Prize (Box 272)
    - Press Clippings (Box 273)
    - Publications, Addresses and Papers, 1962-1972 -Correspondence and related items (Box 274)
    - Publications, Addresses and Papers, 1962-1975 -texts (Box 275)
    - Resignation (Box 276)
    - Seminar, 1963 (Box 276)
    - State Department, (8 Folders) (Box 276)
    - State Education Department (Box 277)
    - Swedish Order of the North Star (Box 277)
    - Tributes (Box 277)
    - Tributes and Condolences (Box 277)
    - U.N.-Miscellaneous (Box 277)
    - U.N. ,U.S. Committee for the (Box 277)
    - U.N. University (Box 278)
    - U.N. University (Box 279)
  - Calendars, 1950, 1962-1975 (Box 280)
  - Calendars, 1968 -1970 (Columbia Presidency) (Box 281)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous Personal, 1970 -1974 (Box 282)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous Personal, 1974 -1975 (Box 283)
- Series VII: Andrew W. Cordier Working Papers 1971-1975
  Personal Correspondence: Six Folders of letters with a variety of people; filed chronologically covering period 1971-1975 (August)
  - A- (Box 284)
  - Angel, William: One Folder of letters concerning his proposed writing project and copies oprospectus-1974 (Box 284)
  - Academies and Councils: Seven Folders of correspondence with educational and international organizations-1971-75 (Box 284)
  - Alumni Relations Office, C. U.: One general letter, December 6, 1973 from Peter Buchanan, Director of University Development and Alumni Relations ,regarding alumni brochure mailing by Columbia University Press. (Box 284)
  - Association of Former International Civil Servants: One Folder of correspondence and material-1973-75. (Box 284)
  - Correspondence with individuals whose surnames begin with "B": One Folder -1971-73. (Box 284)